Minutes of the Executive Council of AFL, Pt. 2 on Microfilm 5918 mf
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Minutes 1950-1952 (Reel 15)
  - 1005. Meeting Minutes of November 25, 1952. 17 pages., 13 (Reel 15)
    Major Topics: American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations unity negotiations; death of William Green; election of George Meany as president of American Federation of Labor; election of William Schnitzler as secretary-treasurer of American Federation of Labor.
- Minutes 1953-1955 (Reel 16)
  - 0001. Meeting Minutes of February 2-9, 1953. 141 pages., 1 (Reel 16)
    Major Topics: American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations unity negotiations; American Federation of Labor litigation; International Automobile Workers Union charter controversy; American Federation of Labor Civil Rights Department established; racketeering among New York Longshoremen; moral rearmament movement; Justice Department ruling on motion picture industry condemned; Postal Workers; Puerto Rico; assistance to Democrats in Congress; American Federation of Labor public relations program; Seafarers International Union dispute with Canadian Seamen's Union; anti-Semitism in Soviet Russia; Taft-Hartley Act amendments; United Textile Workers of America; undulant fever as an occupational disease; American Federation of Labor Report on Wages and Economic Stability; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.
  - 0142. Meeting Minutes of May 20-25, 1953. 153 pages., 2 (Reel 16)
    Major Topics: American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations Unity Committee; American Federation of Labor organization; International Union of United Automobile Workers charter controversy; Building Service Employees dispute with Federation of State, County, and Municipal Employees; National Association for the Advancement of Colored People financial appeal to American Federation of Labor; investigation of Detroit and Wayne County Federation of Labor; Marine Engineers Beneficial Association merger with Masters, Mates, and Pilots; British Trades Union Congress; Gas Workers Federal Labor Union jurisdiction dispute with Building Trades Unions; National Council of Government Employees protest contracts to private industry; International Confederation of Free Trade Unions; racketeering in New York Longshoremen's Unions; Machinists jurisdiction dispute with Building and Construction Trades Department; Brotherhood of Maintenance of Way Employees jurisdiction dispute with building and Construction Trades Department; American Federation of Labor no-raiding agreement with Congress of Industrial Organizations; housing and rent control; union security in Railroad Labor Unions; Taft-Hartley Act amendments; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.
  - 0295. Meeting Minutes of august 10-14, 1953. 136 pages., 3 (Reel 16)
    Major Topics: International Union of United Automobile Workers charter revoked; Building and Construction Trades Department report on jurisdiction disputes; Carpenters opposition to no-raiding agreement with Congress of Industrial Organizations; factionalism in Detroit and Wayne County Federation of Labor; relief fund for East Berlin workers; International Confederation of Free Trade Unions; New York Longshoremen's racketeering; International Longshoremen's Association abolition of "shape-up" system; State, County, and Municipal Employees jurisdiction dispute with Building and Construction Trades Department; Teamsters organization of New York, New York, taxi drivers; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.
  - 0431. Meeting Minutes of September 20-21, 23, 26, and October 14, 1953. 53 pages., 4 (Reel 16)
    Major topics: Building and Construction Trades Department jurisdiction disputes recommendations; Building Service Employees dispute with State, county, and Municipal Employees; International Longshoremen's Association charter revocation; American Federation of Labor-congress of Industrial Organizations unity negotiations; American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations no-raiding agreement; Puerto Rico organizing campaign.
  - 0484. Meeting Minutes of February 1-9, 1954. 129 pages., 5 (Reel 16)
    Major Topics: American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations unity conference; Airline Pilots Association jurisdiction dispute with Machinists; Bricker Amendment; Equal Rights Amendment; Hatters strike in Norwalk, Connecticut; housing; International Confederation of Free Trade Unions; Italian labor movement; American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations no- raiding agreement; congressional hearings on labor racketeering; Mexican migrant agricultural workers; Spanish fascism; German economic situation; National Labor Relations Board; Russia; Taft-Hartley Act amendments; Postal Employees; social security; American Federation of Labor litigation; union health and welfare funds; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.
  - 0610. Meeting Minutes of May 13 and 17-19, 1954. 129 pages., 6 (Reel 16)
    Major Topics: American Federation of Labor litigation; American Federation of Labor constitution recodification; Railway Clerks dispute with Teamsters; unemployment and national economic outlook; housing policy; racial integration, American Federation of Labor statement on Brown versus Board of Education decision; Indochina; Israel; American Federation of Labor jurisdiction dispute plan; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics; Sugar Workers charter application and dispute with Teamsters.
  - 0739. Meeting Minutes of August 9-12, 1954. 64 pages., 7 (Reel 16)
    Major Topics: American federation of Labor policy on internal disputes; Beet Sugar Workers charter application; American Federation of Labor statement on communism; Marine Engineers jurisdiction dispute with Seafarers International Union over Masters, Mates, and Pilots; Federal Labor Unions policies; Airline Pilots Association dispute with flight Engineers; International Longshoremen's Association; racial discrimination in employment in the South; National Urban League; American Federation of Labor finances; American Federation of Labor condemnation of 83rd Congress.
  - 0803. Meeting Minutes of September 19, 24, and 27, 1954. 31 pages., 8 (Reel 16)
    Major Topics: Associated Actors and Artists of America dispute with American Federation of Musicians; Marine Engineers dispute with Seafarers International Union; organization of Los Angeles "News" Company; Teamsters jurisdiction over Sugar workers investigated.
  - 0834. Meeting Minutes of December 15, 1954. 32 pages., 9 (Reel 16)
    Major Topics: Amalgamated Meat Cutters merger with Fur and Leather Workers; Handbags and Novelty Workers merger with Butcher Workmen; American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations merger agreement.
  - 0866. Meeting Minutes of February 1-10, 1955. 128 pages., 10 (Reel 16)
    Major Topics: American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations merger agreement; American Federation of Labor litigation; Berlin, Germany, workers revolt; American Federation of Labor defense of Davis-Bacon Act; Building Service Employees International Union; Defense Mobilization manpower policies; Operating Engineers organization in metal mining industry; federal aid to education; Fur and Leather Workers merger with Amalgamated Meat Cutters; union health and welfare plans; American Federation of Labor policy on internal disputes; International Labor Relations Committee on Europe, Latin America, and Moscow-Peking; Taft-Hartley revision; organization of metal mining and smelting industry; Post Office Employees merger with Building Service Employees; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics; National Labor Relations Board rulings on Taft-Hartley.
  - 0994. Meeting Minutes of May 2-4, 1955. 70 pages., 11 (Reel 16)
    Major Topics: American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations constitution and merger plans; foreign policy toward Europe and Asia; Teamsters request for jurisdiction over Longshoremen; Amalgamated Meat Cutters merger with Fur and Leather Workers; Fair Labor Standards Act revision.
- Minutes 1955 and Executive Council Vote Books 1925-1929 (Reel 17)
  - 0001. Meeting Minutes of May 2-4, 1955 (continued). 22 pages., 1 (Reel 17)
    Major Topic: American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.
  - 0023. Meeting Minutes of August 8-12, 1955. 121 pages., 2 (Reel 17)
    Major Topics: American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations constitution; Building Service Employees suggestions on American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations merger; Electrical Workers suggestion on American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations merger; Flint Glass Workers jurisdiction dispute with glass Bottle Blowers over fabrication of fiberglass; Fur and Leather Workers merger with Meat Cutters and Butcher Workmen; Israel-United States mutual security agreement; Metal Trades Department suggestions on American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations merger; American Federation of Labor statement on Soviet Union; Sleeping Car Porters suggestions on American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations merger; International Typographical Union suggestions on American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations merger; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.
  - 0144. Meeting Minutes of October 24-26 and November 3, 1955. 94 pages., 3 (Reel 17)
    Major Topics: American Federation of Labor- Congress of Industrial Organizations constitution; Air Line Pilots Association jurisdiction dispute with flight Engineers; Flight Engineers strike at United Air Lines; world peace; Fur and Leather Workers objection to merger with Meat Cutters and Butcher Workmen; Italy admission to United Nations; Laundry Workers International Union health and welfare fund; Independent Longshoremen agreement with Teamsters.
  - 0238. Meeting Minutes of November 30 and December 1, 1955. 36 pages., 4 (Reel 17)
    Major Topics: American federation of Labor- Congress of Industrial Organizations Constitutional Convention and merger agreement; Flight Engineers controversy with Air Line Pilots Association; Handbag and Novelty Workers dispute with Meat Cutters and Butcher Workmen; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters suggestions on American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations merger; death of Daniel Tobin.
  - 0274. Executive Council Vote Books. January 1925-December 1925. 188 pages., 5 (Reel 17)
  - 0462. Executive Council Vote Books. January 1926-August 1926. 200 pages., 6 (Reel 17)
  - 0662. Executive Council Vote Books. September 1926-January 1927. 12 pages., 1926-1927; 7 (Reel 17)
  - 0674. Executive Council Vote Books. February 1927-August 1927. 173 pages., 8 (Reel 17)
  - 0847. Executive Council Vote Books. August 1927-July 1929. 219 pages., 1927-1929; 9 (Reel 17)
- Executive Council Vote Books 1929-1935 (Reel 18)
  - 0001. Executive Council Vote Books. July 1929-February 1931. 213 pages., 1929-1931; 1 (Reel 18)
  - 0214. Executive Council Vote Books. February 1931-April 1933. 262 pages., 1931-1933; 2 (Reel 18)
  - 0476. Executive Council Vote Books. April 1933-September 1935. 257 pages., 1933-1935; 3 (Reel 18)
- Executive Council Vote Books 1935-1954 (Reel 19)
  - 0001. Executive Council Vote Books. September 1935-April 1938. 358 pages., 1935-1938; 1 (Reel 19)
  - 0359. Executive Council Vote Books. April 1938-December 1944. 337 pages., 1938-1944; 2 (Reel 19)
  - 0696. Executive Council Vote Book. November 1944-September 1954. 290 pages., 1944-1954; 3 (Reel 19)